《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
但愿那老家伙法尔科内能出点意外
I wish something would happen to old man Falcone.
到时谁来接手呢
who would take over then?
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
马罗尼和军械库的抢劫无关
Maroni had nothing to do with the armory job.
显然  您这儿有个内奸
You have a mole, obviously.
某个和您很亲近的人
Someone close to you.
阿卡姆精神病院
Arkham Asylum?
去给疯子做保安
Security guard for nut-jobs?
罪犯疯子  没错
Criminal nut-jobs, yeah.
用金属针插入大脑
Metal needles were inserted into the brain
直接对额叶进行电击
and electricity was applied to his frontal lobes.
你去查明是哪位可爱的病友干的这事
I want you to find out which one of our inmates did this.
好样的  艾伦
Well done, Aaron.
就像我嘱咐的那样
Exactly like I told you.
你是我目前最棒的作品
Now you are my best work so far.
本剧集字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译制作
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再整理而成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
翻译：草草   木浅薰   爵士年代蓬蓬裙   charcie
翻译：Silence   DustD   Reginamoon
阿卡姆疯子二人组逃院
时间轴：最可爱的小胖子    spohy    萌
特效&后期：鱼骨头   宝宝          校对&总监：草草
欧文电子批发  电子产品供应
欧文电子
需要服务请按铃
不  不行
No. No, no.
货必须是崭新的
The merchandise has got to be mint,
否则我就不付钱
or you won't get a dime.
天哪
My God.
杰克
Jack.
你好  欧文
Hi, Irwin.
我的东西呢
Where's my stuff?
艾伦・丹泽
Aaron Danzig.
一米九五  105公斤
Six-four, 225.
心理年龄还停留在少儿阶段
Mental age of a young child.
我们认为他是受此人的控制
We believe he's under the control of this man,
杰克・格鲁伯
Jack Gruber.
因强奸杀人进了阿卡姆
In Arkham off a rape/murder beef.
我们找不到格鲁伯
We can't find any records on Gruber
入狱前的记录
prior to his incarceration,
所以我们认为这是化名
so we're guessing Gruber is an alias.
我们已经在全国范围搜索他的指纹
We're sending his prints nationwide,
希望能找到他的真实身份
see if we can find another name for him.
不管他是谁  他聪明  愤怒
Whoever he is, he's clever and angry
且严重威胁公众
and a grave public menace.
局长非常关心此事
The commissioner is deeply concerned,
他正在赶来
and he's on his way here
要和你们大家见个面
to talk to all of you right now.
你们都清楚这意味着什么
You know what that means.
要知道
And you know...
吉姆
Jim?
警监
Captain.
你好  搭档
Hey, partner.
这里不是你的辖区
You're out of your jurisdiction.
警监  这是我的案子
Captain, this is my case.
吉姆  你马上给我离开这里
Jim, you need to get out of here.
-这是我的案子  -不不不
- It's my case. - No, no, no.
警监说的对
The captain is right.
你得在局长到之前离开这里
You need to leave before the commissioner gets here.
为什么
Why?
因为他会把这些都算在你头上
Because he holds you responsible for all of this,
而且  倒霉  他已经到了
and... oh, fudge. He's here.
你要被他看到了  躲一下
And you're there. Sidestep.
艾森警监
Captain Essen.
早上好  局长
Good morning, Commissioner.
是戈登警卫吧
Officer Gordon, isn't it?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
你为什么在这儿
Why are you here?
我有个更好的问题
I have a better question.
你为什么在这儿  局长
Why are you here, Commissioner?
-你说什么  -这是我第一次
- Excuse me? - This is the first
见你来到基层
I've seen you down here with the rank and file.
你一定很心急吧
You must be desperate.
跟我走
Follow me.
这辈子认识你很高兴
Really nice knowing you.
把你的朋友布洛克也带上
Bring you friend Bullock.
我恨你
I hate you.
不是我想那么干的  是你朋友
It wasn't my idea; it was your friend.
是他提出背叛你
He came up with the double-cross,
还逼我合作
made me go along.
但你自己也会思考的  不是吗
You have a mind of your own, don't you?
拜托
Hey, come on.
你看
See?
我好好保存着你的东西呢
I kept your gadgets safe.
我知道它对你和你的实验来说多么重要
I know what it means to you, all your experiments.
我很感激
Oh, I appreciate that.
求你
Please.
你不用杀我的
You don't have to kill me.
我不用
I don't...
听从任何人的命令
have to do anything.
我是自由的
I'm free.
你知道讽刺的是什么吗
You know the funny thing?
我想是在阿卡姆度过的日子让我找到了自由
I think it was my time in Arkham that freed me.
我是说
I mean,
思想的自由
in here.
现在我终于认清了世界
Now I see the world for what it really is.
一座满是破损机器的废弃工厂
An abandoned factory full of broken machines.
其中一些
Some--
不过少之又少
very few--
是可以修好的
can be fixed.
大部分
Most...
只能报废了
just have to be scrapped.
丹泽  把住他
Danzig, hold him, please.
求你了
Please.
求你别这样  别这样
Please, no, stop. Please.
求你了  求求你
Please! Please!
两个疯子逃之夭夭
Two maniacs on the loose
也给整个阿卡姆项目蒙羞了  不是吗
makes the whole Arkham Project look kind of shady, huh?
投资人一定坐不住了吧
The moneymen want results fast, I bet.
你居然还敢这样自以为是
You're strangely self-righteous,
病人逃走难道不是你的责任吗
given that it was you that let these men escape.
让我背黑锅无所谓  反正我已经声名狼藉了
Blame me all you want. My name's already mud.
但那两人还在逃
Those two will still be out there,
所以你需要我
and that means you need me.
詹姆斯  你为什么要当警察呢
James, why did you become a policeman?
你父亲是个地检官
Your father was the district attorney.
多好的职位  最适合有身份的人
A proud station for a man of substance.
下一代难道不该受其激励  也以法律为职吗
You would think that would inspire a son to practice law.
我就是在执行法律
I'm enforcing the law.
你是想继续说我爸呢
You want to talk about my dad
还是想抓住格鲁伯和丹泽
or do you want to catch Gruber and Danzig?
你心里那股叛逆的怒火是哪来的
Where do you get the rebellious fire in your belly?
我能不能插个嘴
Can I take this opportunity to say
我不叛逆  也不愤怒  一点没有
that I have no rebellious fire here, nada.
杰克・格鲁伯还在逃
Jack Gruber is out there,
图谋不轨
planning a catastrophe.
我了解这个人
I know the man.
我知道他在想什么
I know how he thinks.
我知道他下一步会干什么
I know what he'll do next.
是什么
Which is what?
现在还不能说
That I'll keep to myself.
我保证会将这两人捉拿归案
I guarantee I'll bring in these two men,
但首先  你得复我的职
but first, I need you to reinstate me
让我重新成为哥谭市警局的一级警探
as detective first grade in the GCPD.
你这是勒索  戈登警员
Extortion, Officer Gordon.
给你一天时间
24 hours?
-什么  -你们有一天时间去抓这两个人
- What? - You've got 24 hours to bring these men in.
如果没抓到  你们两个下半辈子
You don't, you can both spend the rest
就给我待在阿卡姆吧
of your miserable careers down at Arkham.
就这样  二位警探
That will be all, Detectives.
什么情况
What the hell just happened?
没事的  没事
It's okay, it's okay.
-不会有事的  哈维  -是吗
- Everything's gonna be fine, Harvey. - Yeah?
当然  只要抓到那两个坏蛋就好了
Yeah, we just got to catch the bad guys.
-行啊  上哪去抓  -不知道
- Okay, where are we going? - I don't know.
什么  你刚不是还说知道格鲁伯下一步计划吗
What? You just told him you knew what Gruber was gonna do next.
我骗人的
I lied.
哥谭
第一季  第十二集
求你了  法尔科内阁下  饶了我吧
Please, Don Falcone, have mercy.
我们是家人啊
We're family.
我知道  孩子
I know, son.
我知道这很难
I know it's hard.
你还这么年轻
A young man like you,
死了太不公平了
it doesn't seem fair.
求求你
Please.
法尔科内阁下  求求你了
Don Falcone, please!
小时候  这片都是贫民窟
This whole area used to be slums when I was a boy.
您真不容易
You've come a long way.
您的一些手下在找您呢
Some of your people are looking for you, you know.
但我只想见你
But you're the one I wanted to see.
我奋斗了这么久才取得今天的成就
I've worked so long all my life to get where I am.
久到我已经忘了当初为什么要奋斗
So long, I forget why I wanted to be here.
您想要成为大人物
Well, you wanted to be someone.
现在您已经是了
And you are.
瞧瞧您拥有的这些啊
Look at all the stuff you have.
你是个好姑娘  莉莎
You're a good girl, Liza.
你应该找一个年轻人  和他结婚生子
You need to find a young man and get married, have babies.
把你留在我身边  困在这里打理家务
It's not fair of me, keeping you cooped up here,
实在太自私了
doing my housework.
你在这里是找不到好丈夫的
You'll never find a good husband here.
如果你想要出去闯闯
Anyhow, if you'd like to get out in the world,
我可以送你一个面包店
I was thinking I could set you up with a bakery
或者别的小店
or some type of business like that.
这样你就可以独立生活了
So you can be independent.
您真好  法先生  谢谢
That's really nice, Mr. F. Thank you.
但我更想和您在一起
But I would rather be here with you.
真的吗
You would?
我很喜欢这里
I like it here.
您让我觉得很安全
You make me feel safe.
好
Well, good.
我也喜欢你陪在身边
I like having you here.
好吧
Yeah.
晚餐前我还有点事要办
Maybe I'll try to get a little work done before dinner.
今晚我要做顿丰盛晚餐
I'm making something special tonight.
你笑什么
What are you laughing at?
回来真好
Ah, it's good to be back.
只有疯人院回来的人才会这么说
Only a man from a lunatic asylum would say that.
你就像个人类过山车
You're like a human roller coaster,
只是你只往低处走
except you only go down.
那他不是更像电梯吗
Wouldn't that make him more of an elevator?
有什么有用的消息吗  爱德
You have anything useful, Ed?
还有不到20小时我就要失业了
I got a little less than 20 hours before I lose my job.
我确实  有点有用的消息
I do -- have something useful.
是什么
And it is?
我交叉对比了指纹
I cross-checked fingerprints.
阿卡姆的精神病人杰克・格鲁伯
The clinically insane Jack Gruber of Arkham
只是文件上的虚假身份
is a figment of the files.
他本人实际上是个职业罪犯
The man himself is really a career criminal
叫做杰克・布钦斯基
by the name Jack Buchinsky.
这怎么可能啊
How is that even possible?
收买个人改份文件记录是很容易的
Easy enough to bribe someone to change the records.
是  看来他很想转去阿卡姆
Yep, apparently, he wanted to be transferred to Arkham.
干的真棒  爱德
That's really good work, Ed.
这布闲斯基又是谁啊
What's this Buttinsky's deal?
是布钦斯基
Uh, it's, uh, Buchinsky.
他的事都在文件里
It's all in the files.
带出去时要签名
Just make sure you sign it out.
这是机密信息  要谨慎处理
It's classified information, so just be careful.
柯林格小姐
Miss Kringle?
我想这个是你落在我桌上的
I believe you left this on my desk.
这是个谜语
It's a riddle.
这是个露着截子弹的纸杯蛋糕
It's a cupcake with a live bullet sticking out of it.
这是个谜语
It's a riddle.
这恐怖  古怪  而且不宜食用
It's menacing and weird and inedible.
谢谢你的文件  柯林格小姐
Thank you for the files, Miss Kringle.
这个布钦斯基和他的同伙
This Buchinsky dude and his partners
四次成功抢劫银行
pulled four successful bank robberies,
被哥谭市警局意外抓获前还杀过
killed six along the way before the GCPD caught him
六个人
by accident.
他一直未供出同伙的名字
He never named his accomplices.
他在监狱里时
He's in prison,
听说阿卡姆重新开门了
he hears Arkham is opening its doors,
于是动用了点关系
so he uses his connections,
给自己弄了个新身份
and he gets himself a new identity
就是精神病人格鲁伯
as the mental patient Gruber.
他找的关系肯定挺厉害
He must have some good connections.
没错  其他疯子也被送进阿卡姆后
Right, and when the rest of the nuts get transferred to Arkham --
好戏就上演了
voila.
他当时有同伙
So, he had partners, huh?
哥谭市警局还不知道是谁
Yeah, GCPD never identified them.
他们还在逍遥法外
They're still out there.
是的  找到他们  就能找到他
Yep, we find them, we'll find him.
很简单吧
Easy enough, huh?
警探
Detective.
被劫货车被弃于工业园区
线索来了
A hit.
阿卡姆疯人院犯人运送车辆
有什么发现
What do we got?
警员撒粉提取了指纹  找到两个人的
Lead detectives dusted for prints, two sets--
格鲁伯和丹泽的  跟我们想的一样
Gruber and Danzig, just like we thought.
好  谢谢  好吧
Right. Thanks. All right.
货车没错了  是他们
Van checks out. It was them.
这人对用电作案很着迷是吧
Our man's an electronics freak, right?
没错
Yeah.
觉得他会不会是去买东西了
Think he went shopping?
欧文电子
死了  电的外焦里嫩的
He's dead. Fried like a doughnut.
哥谭市警局
GCPD.
转过身  把手举起来
Turn around slowly, let me see those hands.
伙计
Hey, buddy.
我不背叛朋友
救命  救命啊
Help, help! Please!
滚回去
Get back in the store.
好啦  没事
Okay. Take it easy. Okay.
求求你  这一定是个误会
Please, there's been a terrible mistake.
我只是法尔科内阁下的管家
I am Don Falcone's housekeeper.
菲什  谢天谢地
Fish? Thank God.
你干吗那样把我拉来
Why'd you have to pull me out like that?
你吓死我了
You scared the life out of me.
是时候了  莉莎
It's time, Liza.
我要对法尔科内下手了
I'm gonna make my move on Falcone.
别害怕  小姑娘
And don't be scared, baby girl.
有我呢
I got this.
法尔科内先生  你女人莉莎在我这儿
Mr. Falcone, we have your girl, Liza.
你还想再见她吗
Would you like to see her again?
当然  我想
Yes, I would.
她听到一定会很高兴
She'll be glad to hear that.
这么健康的年轻姑娘  对疼痛的忍耐力真差
For a fit young woman, she has a low pain threshold.
求你了  住手  别打了
Please! No! Stop!
很快会有中间人联系你的
An intermediary will be in contact with you soon.
别伤害她  她只是个普通人
Don't hurt her. She's a civilian.
喂
Hello?
现在怎么办
What now?
让他坐着  思考一下人生
Now we let him sit and think about his life for a while.
电刑人袭人
"电刑人"  真好听
"The Electrocutioner." cute.
别有压力
No pressure.
不用担心  一定能抓到他
Don't worry, we'll get him.
是啊  就剩17个小时了
Yeah, and we got 17 hours to do so.
这名字我喜欢
I love the name.
朗朗上口  有个性
It's catchy, has drama.
电  刑  人
The Electro-cutioner.
话说  根据他通常的袭击方式
Speaking of which, given the general mode of attack,
我建议两位...
may I suggest you both wear your...
外出办案时穿上警局配发的橡胶鞋
department-issue galoshes while you're out in the field.
橡胶鞋
Galoshes?
万一发生触电的意外事故
In the event of electrical misadventure,
你们的鞋子得绝缘才行
your footwear should be insulated.
不要啦  老妈  我才不穿橡胶鞋呢
No, Mom! I'm not gonna wear my rubbers on the case.
尼格玛  把鞋给我
Nygma, give 'em here.
不是吧
Seriously?
说说目前什么情况
All right, so what do we know?
格鲁伯对欧文很不满
Gruber wasn't too happy with Irwin.
也许他俩以前一起作案  欧文背叛了他
Maybe they were partners in crime, Irwin turned on him,
结果格鲁伯被抓
Gruber took the fall.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon.
汤普金斯医生
Dr. Thompkins.
朋友都叫我小莱
My friends call me Lee.
恭喜  你又能回来工作了
Congratulations, you got your job back.
还不一定  看情况
Or not, depending.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
是吗
Is it?
我知道你正忙着抓逃犯
I-I know you're caught up with the escape.
我就是因为这个来的
That's why I'm here.
一切还好吧
Is everything okay?
一定都乱作一团了
Must be chaos down there.
我们还能撑住  谢谢关心
We're getting by just fine. Thanks for asking.
对了  这是我搭档  哈维・布洛克
Oh, right, this is my partner, Harvey Bullock.
好啊
Hola.
布洛克警探
Detective Bullock.
你手上拿的是什么
Who's your little friend there?
我就是为了这个来的
Oh, this is why I'm here.
我工作的囚区  有个女人是女巫
One of the women in my wing is a pagan sorceress.
当然了
Of course.
她很受欢迎
She's very popular.
病人们做娃娃  做成他们想要诅咒的人的样子
The inmates make dolls to look like people that they want to curse.
然后女巫替他们诅咒这些娃娃
And then they give it to the sorceress to curse them.
用苏打水和糖作为交换
In exchange for extra soda and candy.
我经常诅咒你  也没见你给我糖吃啊
I curse you all the time. You never give me candy.
我问她格鲁伯有没有给过她娃娃让她诅咒
I asked her if Gruber had ever given her a doll to curse,
她说有
and she said yes.
这就是他的娃娃  他叫M先生
This is the doll. His name is Mr. M.
你欠我12罐沙士
You owe me for a double six-pack of root beer.
M先生
Mr. M.?
Mr. M.
M先生
你觉得这像谁
Who does this look like to you?
我和这人说  莫里斯
I tell this guy, I said, "Maurice--
我们已经拔了你半颗牙了
we've pulled out half your freaking teeth.
你还他妈等什么呢
What the hell are you waiting for?
牙仙吗
The tooth fairy?" Right?
欧文电子批发  电子产品供应
他做了什么
So, what he does...
知道莫里斯做了什么吗  他对我笑
you know what Maurice does? He smiles at me.
然后我说  我要再拔你一颗牙
So I say, "I'm gonna take out another one, man."
我准备拔他的臼齿
I go to his molar.
我叫马里奥和盖布帮我一起拔
I got to get Mario and Gabe to help me pull it out.
失陪一下
Do excuse me.
我们就这样使劲拔
Right. So, we're, like, pulling it,
使劲拔
we're pulling it, right?
终于拔出来了
And finally we get it out.
那牙有这么大
The thing is this big...
是我
Yes.
来见我  我需要你
Come see me. I need you.
这就来  发生了什么事
I'm on my way. What's wrong?
有人抓走了莉莎  快点过来
Somebody took Liza. Come, quickly.
你个狡猾的魔鬼
You sly devil.
你把她抓走了
You took her.
现在你是我的囊中物了
You're mine now.
我就告诉这人说  让他说话吧
So I'm trying to tell this guy, "Let him talk."
因为他现在想说话  可我却听不懂
Because now he's trying to talk, but now I don't understand him
因为他没了牙齿
'cause he's got no teeth, right?
所以我说  让他说话  帮他清理干净
So I'm saying, "Let him talk. Clean him out.
他要告诉我们什么事呢
He's gonna tell us something."
马罗尼阁下  请原谅我
Don Maroni, Sir, forgive me.
大家都这么开心
Such fun we're having.
但可惜我必须先走了
But I regret that I must run away.
如果您允许的话
If you'll let me.
我母亲生病了
My mother is sick.
母亲生病了是大事
Well, a sick mother's a sick mother.
去吧
Go.
巴蒙特餐馆
企鹅  没事吧
Penguin, you all right?
小子  你...
Hey, kid, what are you...?
发生什么事了
What's going on here?
快趴下
Get down!
不知道发生了什么事
I don't know what happened.
就像是个无声的炸弹
It was like a silent bomb.
你知道是谁干的吧
You know who did this, right?
谁
Who?
几年前  杰克・布钦斯基
A few years ago, Jack Buchinsky
和他不明身份的同伙抢劫了四间银行
and partners unknown knocked over four banks.
杀死六个人
Killed six people.
布钦斯基被判终身监禁
Buchinsky went down for life.
而他的同伙一直未落网
His partners were never caught.
你就是其中一名同伙
You're one of those partners.
你拿了他应得的一份  出卖了他
The one that took his share and sold him up the river, I expect.
这人是谁
What guy was this?
布...
Bu... uh...
布什么
Who?
他现在在找机会报复你
While he's out there looking to hurt you,
根本不管是否祸及他人
he doesn't care who else he hurts.
包括妇孺  小孩
Women, kids.
这不是我的错
That's not my fault.
帮助我抓到他  马罗尼阁下
Help me do the right thing here, Don Maroni.
让我带你回去进行保护性监禁
Let me place you in protective custody.
保护性监禁
Protective custody?
是的
Yes.
是拿我当诱饵吧
Bait, you mean.
我们抓到坏人
We catch our bad guy,
你也能摆脱危险人物
you get rid of a dangerous nuisance.
双方都受益
We both come out ahead.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
有人吗
Hello?
我必须要走
I... must be going.
我有非常紧急的事
Very urgent business.
要找法尔科内
W-W-With Falcone.
好了
All right,
你自便吧
make yourself at home.
甜心
Hey, sweetheart.
给我拿杯双倍特浓咖啡
Get me a double espresso.
多加糖
Extra sugar.
我是芭芭拉
I'm Barbara.
芭芭拉・基恩
Barbara Kean.
我父母  他们住在这里
My parents, they live here.
见到你真高兴  芭芭拉
It's very nice to see you, Barbara.
是不是  埃弗雷特
Isn't it, Everett?
是的  很高兴
Yes, very nice.
见到您我也很高兴
It's nice to see you, too.
近来还好吧
You've been well, I hope?
好
Yes.
您呢
And you?
棒极了
Splendid.
你要留下来住一晚吗
Are you staying the night?
假如可以的话
Uh, if that's all right.
实际上...
In fact, um...
我想着也许我可以待上几天
I-I thought maybe I could stay a few days.
假如那样...
If that's...
我明白了
Oh, I see.
好的  当然没问题
Yes, of course.
我想你一定会觉得无聊至极
I'm sure you're going to be frightfully bored.
但是想一直待到周末的话
But stay until the weekend.
当然没问题
By all means.
谢谢您
Thank you.
你那位怎样了
How's that young man of yours?
詹姆斯
James?
那个警察
The policeman?
一切都还好吧
All well, I hope?
挺好的
Yes.
他很好  谢谢
He's well, thank you.
那就好
Good.
我们很幸福
We're very happy.
非常幸福
Very happy.
你们似乎都很喜欢听笑话啊
You guys are, like, hungry for this.
你们在这里都是怎么找乐子的
What do you guys do here for excitement?
还记得那个笑话吗  关于那什么来着
Remember that joke about the, uh, what is it?
两个警察和一位殡仪员一起上了渔船
The two cops and the undertaker that go on a fishing boat.
要是拴头羊作诱饵
When you use a tethered goat as bait,
不是该把羊放进丛林里而不是关在房间里吗
shouldn't the goat be out in the jungle and not in the house?
这间房子是哥谭防卫最严的地方
This house is the best-defended spot in Gotham.
布钦斯基疯狂自大还很诡计多端
Buchinsky is crazy and arrogant and resourceful.
不管马罗尼在哪里  他都会找来
Wherever Maroni is, he'll come after him.
他会享受这挑战
He'll enjoy the challenge.
你好啊
Hey, there.
老大
Hi... hi, boss.
我昏迷了多久
How long have I been unconscious?
几小时
Couple of hours.
天呐
Oh, my gosh.
我必须得走了
I-I must go.
我可怜的妈妈...
My-my poor mother...
让你妈妈等吧
Your mother can wait.
是她的心脏出问题了
It's her heart, poor thing.
心脏瓣膜
Valves.
她随时都可能离世...
She-she might be taken at any moment...
但是  当然了
But... but, by all means,
当然了  她可以等
of course, she can wait.
你之前醒来时
When you woke up before,
你说你有紧急事务...
you said you had urgent business...
要找法尔科内
with Falcone.
真的吗
I did?
我那样说了吗
I said that?
真的
Did I?
卡麦
Carmine?
有人给我打电话说你的莉莎的事
Some people have called me about your girl Liza.
他们想要我帮忙做笔交易
They want me to help make a deal.
我没想到会是你
I didn't think it was going to be you.
真遗憾
I'm sorry.
我只是个中间人
I'm just an intermediary.
我只是想帮忙
I just want to help.
行了  亲爱的
Please, my dear.
够了
Stop.
我知道是你干的
I know this is you.
实诚点吧
Be honest.
是我
It's me.
果然如此
Of course it is.
咱们认识多久了
How long have I known you?
你是家族里最聪明的那一个
You're the smart one in the family.
我总是这么说
Didn't I always say so?
她不会受到伤害
She won't be hurt.
离开高谭
Leave Gotham.
仅此而已  离开高谭
That's all-- leave Gotham,
永远别回来
never come back.
你可以带走她
You can take her with you.
好的
Agreed.
这个决定很正确  我会去安排
That's the right decision. I'll make the arrangements.
你一直是我最喜欢的那个
You were always my favorite.
等我电话
Wait for my call.
他要走了
He's leaving?
你成功了
You did it?
老大
Boss?
那智慧  那眼界
The genius! The-the vision!
你终于搞掉了老头子
You brought down the old man... finally.
我们来庆祝吧
Let's celebrate.
布奇  现在不是庆祝的时候
Butch, this is not the time to celebrate.
他曾经是位伟大的人
He was a great man once.
如果他留下  别人也会干掉他
You don't think somebody would take him out if he stayed on?
我是在帮他忙  给了他条轻松的出路
I am doing him a favor and giving him an easy way out.
这是我欠他的
I owe him at least that.
当然
Of course.
你说的没错
You're right.
这样对大家都好
It's best for everyone.
他听起来怎么样
How did he sound?
伤心
Sad.
看着我
Look at me.
你有事瞒着我吗
Is there something you're not telling me?
没有
No.
你得和他一起离开城市
You're going to have to leave town with him,
跟他待一阵子
string him along for a while.
你觉得你能做到吗
Do you think you can do that?
可以
Sure.
不过你喜欢他  对不对
But you like him, though, don't you?
我可以喜欢他的吧
Well, I can like him, can't I?
他一直非常绅士
He's been a perfect gentleman.
他本可做出各种事
He could've done anything,
可他从没对我有非分之举
and he never laid a hand on me.
莉莎  你想怎么喜欢他都行
Liza, you can like him all you want.
但你绝不能告诉他真相
But you can never tell him the truth.
我知道
I know that.
阁下
Sir?
让我去搞定吧
Let me go to work.
不用
No.
"No"?
如果菲什和其他人
If Fish and the others--
肯定还有其他人
and there must be others--
如果他们这么想让我退位
if they all want me to step away so badly,
那也许该是时候了
maybe it's time.
为什么不呢
Why not?
我还挣扎什么
Why am I still here fighting?
为了什么呢
For what?
为了尊重
For respect.
您是卡麦・法尔科内阁下
You're Don Carmine Falcone.
尊重
"Respect"?
谁在乎
Who cares?
他们都想让我去乡下跟莉莎一起生活
They all want me to go live in the country with Liza.
这也不错
I would like that.
我也想这样
That's what I want, too.
所以  为什么不照办呢
So, why not do it?
求您...
Please...
别说这种话  阁下
don't talk that way, sir.
只要我出马
And just me on my own?
我可以轻松干掉菲什的人马
I can take out Fish's crew easy.
你没在听  维克多
You're not listening, Victor.
你的工作是保护我和莉莎的安全
Your job is to keep me and Liza safe
直到交易完成
through the coming transaction.
仅此而已
That's all.
是  阁下
Yes, sir.
柯林格小姐
Miss Kringle?
干什么  干什么啊
What?! What?
杯型蛋糕很甜  子弹很致命
The cupcake is sweet, the bullet is deadly.
美丽的女人有致命的威力
A beautiful woman's a dangerous thing.
那个....
Um, uh, listen, I, uh...
这真是...
That is so...
我不...
I don't...
我都不知道该说什么了
I don't even know what to say to that.
尼格玛  你个变态  走开吧
Nygma, you perv, back off.
看不出人家姑娘嫌你烦吗
Can't you see the lady doesn't want you bugging her?
我
I, um...
你好啊  谁在烦谁了
Hey, there. Hey, now. Who's bugging who?
我只是...
I'm just, I'm just...
什么东西比红更绿
What's green and then red?
搅拌机里的青蛙
Frogs in a blender.
走开吧  尼格玛
Walk away, Nygma.
走开
Walk away.
如果我冒犯了你我很抱歉  柯林格小姐
I'm very sorry if I've offended you, Miss Kringle.
我绝无此意
That was not my intention.
你们听到了吗
Do you hear that?
走开
Go.
谢谢
Thank you.
他好怪啊
He is so weird.
我跟法尔科内毫无瓜葛
I have no business with Falcone!
我以我母亲的性命发誓
I swear on my mother's life!
如果我撒谎  就让上帝
May God strike her dead with horrible torment
令她惨死吧
if I'm lying!
好吧  朋友
Okay, then, my friend.
抱歉我怀疑了你
I'm sorry I doubted you.
去见妈妈吧
Go see your mom.
替我带好
Give her a kiss for me.
谢谢
Thank you.
就是他
There's the one.
被那个滑稽的家伙压在身下
Under that funny-looking fellow there.
把他带上车
Take him to the truck.
他们没烤焦
They didn't cook.
只是昏过去了
Just stunned.
我以为会更...
I expected more...
厉害点呢
oomph!
你要厉害的  杰克
You want "Oomph," Jack?
戈登警卫
Officer Gordon.
鞋子不错啊
Nice shoes.
是戈登警探
Detective Gordon.
你俩举起手
Hands up, both of you.
你还是把枪放下吧
You might want to drop that.
何必跟我作对  戈登
Why fight me, Gordon?
这里有谁
Who here
值得你保护
deserves your protection?
-有吗  -都值得
- Any of them? - All of them.
甚至马罗尼吗  得了吧
Even Maroni?! Please!
让我杀了这背信弃义的朋友
Just let me kill this false friend
继续生活吧
and get on with my life.
打得这么卖力
All this fight.
是为了什么呢
And for what?
我要把你关回阿卡姆  杰克
I'm putting you back in Arkham, Jack.
这才更接近真相  对吗  吉姆
That's closer to the mark, now, isn't it, Jim?
你需要赢  对吗
You need to win. Don't you?
你假装在乎法律
You pretend to care about the law,
但你真正的初衷  不过是骄傲
but in your heart, it's all primitive ego.
和对暴力及权力的渴望
And you lust for blood and power.
你只是不喜欢输
You just hate to lose.
告诉你
You know what?
你说对了
You're right.
我是不喜欢输
I do hate to lose.
恭喜你  年轻人
Congratulations, young man.
新的一天到来了
A new day.
是啊
New day.
下次再有人想夺走我的警徽
Next man that tries to take away my shield...
不管怎样
one way or another,
我要让他吃不了兜着走
I'm gonna make him eat it.
你说什么
Say again?
新的一天啊  局长
New day, Commissioner.
希望你有他的艳照做把柄
I hope you have some nasty pictures of him,
因为我敢说你刚刚一定撂了狠话
because I bet what you said was very, very rude.
我再也不要小心翼翼了
I'm done being careful.
你觉得你之前一直很小心吗
You think you've been careful so far?
洛布局长这种人是不会信任我的
Men like Commissioner Loeb are never gonna trust me.
你觉得你之前一直很小心吗
You think you've been careful so far?
何必跟他们客气呢
So why play nice?
你觉得
You think...
你之前一直很小心吗
you've been careful so far?
别担心
Don't worry.
我心里有数
I know what I'm doing.
我们去喝杯啤酒吧
Let's go grab a beer.
你这是糊弄我呢
Now you're messing with my mind.
我需要比酒劲头大的东西
I need something stronger than a beer.
安静  年轻人
Hush, young man.
我听得到你叹气
I can hear you sigh.
抱歉  先生
Sorry, sir.
让他过来
Let him be.
见到你很高兴  老朋友
It's good to see you, old friend.
很抱歉我这么晚才过来
I am so sorry it took me so long to get here.
今天我过得真是...
Such a day I've had...
我就不跟你您说了
I won't even tell you.
但我来了
But I'm here.
你对菲什的看法是对的
You were right about Fish.
是她劫走了莉莎
It's her that's taken Liza.
先生  允许我...
Sir, allow me...
我必须把我发现的事告诉你
I must tell you what I've discovered.
这话不太中听
You're not gonna want to hear this.
说吧
Speak.
莉莎是菲什有意插在您身边的
Liza was planted on you by Fish.
她是菲什的人
She belongs to Fish.
从头就是个陷阱
This was a setup from the start.
她找到个像您母亲的女孩
She found a girl that looked just like your mother,
训练好她
and trained her up...
不
No.
对不起
I'm sorry.
-拿出证明  -怎么证明
- Prove that. - How?
我做不到
I-I can't.
但我知道
I just know.
你错了
You're wrong.
我什么时候错过
When have I been wrong?
你好  菲什
Hello, Fish.
法尔科内阁下
Don Falcone.
我们在我这儿见面
We will meet at my place.
可以吗
Acceptable?
可以
Yes.
她在吗  莉莎在那儿吗
Is she there? Is Liza there now?
我能跟她谈谈吗
Can I speak to her?
不行
No.
什么时候
What time?
一小时后
In an hour.
我会去的
I'll be there.
菲什
Fish.
法尔科内阁下
Don Falcone.
我们怎么做
How's this work?
莉莎就在附近
Liza is close by.
我只需要你签文件
All I need for you to do is sign papers--
将家族的大权交出来
relinquish all control of the family--
然后你们就可以一起离开
and then you're both free to leave.
文件
Papers?
你以为有了文件就是老大了
You think papers make a don?
我给了你一条出路  卡麦
I'm offering you a way out, Carmine.
我明白
I appreciate that.
谢谢
Thank you.
但我要先见到她
But I need to see her first.
我签字之前
Before I sign anything,
我要确认她没事
I need to know she's all right.
她没事
She's fine.
我得见到她
I need to see her.
否则免谈
Or no deal.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
我没事
I'm okay.
你认识菲什・穆尼多久了
How long have you known Fish Mooney?
我不认识她
I don't.
我今天才见到她
I just met her now.
不
No.
有只小鸟告诉我
A little bird told me you and she
你们已经认识很久了
have been friends for a while.
不是的
No.
还说她跟你讲了关于我母亲的事
Told me that she told you stuff about my mother
好让你把我迷住
so that I'd get all caught up in you.
因为菲什知道
Because Fish knows.
知道我母亲的事
You know, about my mother.
你知道我多爱我母亲
You know how much I loved my mother,
因为我们谈过她的事
because we talked about her
我们经常谈起她
all the time, you and me.
记得吗  菲什  以前的时候
Remember, Fish? Back in the day?
记得
I do.
看来这只小鸟是在说谎了
It seems as though a little bird has been making a bit of mischief.
是啊
Yes.
我也希望是那样
That's what I had hoped.
但真相显而易见
But the truth is plain to see.
我对自己的愚蠢十分失望
I am very disappointed at my own stupidity.
对不起  莉莎
I'm sorry, Liza.
你是叫这个吗
Is that your name?
抱歉你卷进了这些事中
I'm sorry you had to get mixed up in this,
我相信你一定是个...
because I'm sure you're a...
诚实的好姑娘
good, honest girl, really.
别
No.
暂时留他俩一命
I want these two alive for now.
把他们关起来
Lock them up someplace.
别大喊求救了
Don't bother yelling for help.
你的人都死了
All your people are dead.
卡麦
Carmine...
你得明白...
you have to under...
我可以原谅各种背叛和谎言
I can forgive all kinds of betrayal and dishonesty.
但我母亲
But my mother?
你怎么敢用我神圣的母亲来对付我
How dare you use my sainted mother against me?
这太过分了
That's wrong!
-你要为此付出代价  -你得...
- You'll suffer for that. - I need you to...
谢谢  菲什
Thank you, Fish.
很久以来
For the first time in a long time,
我第一次感觉如此鲜活
I feel alive.
我记起了我的身份
I remember who I am.
我记起了我如何走到今天
I remember why I'm here.
-求你  -你可以出来了
- Just... - You can come out now.
你又说对了  我的朋友
Right, as usual, my friend.
快点道别吧
Say your good-byes quickly.
穆尼女士还有地方要去呢
Ms. Mooney has places to go.
你好啊  菲什
Hello, Fish.
男更衣室
汤普金斯医生
Dr. Thompkins.
小莱
Lee.
接待警员说我可以进来
The desk sergeant said it was okay to come back here.
我无意打扰你的
I didn't mean to disturb you.
没事  有什么事吗
No, no. It's okay. Something wrong?
没事
No.
我就是正好在这一带
I was in the area,
我的女巫想要回她的娃娃
and, um... my sorceress wants her doll back.
嗯  好的
Right, yeah.
你是为这事来的吗
Is that why you're here?
是
Yes.
也不是
No.
她的确想要回娃娃  但是...
She does want her doll back, but, um...
也不全是为这个
Not entirely. No.
你住这儿啊
You live here?
我现在还在找住处
Sort of between places right now.
我不知道我为什么来
I don't know why I'm here.
抱歉
Sorry.
就是一时兴起
A whim.
等等
Wait.
戈登  听说了吗
Hey, Gordon, did you hear?
菲什・穆尼那儿发生了激烈枪战
There's been a big shootout at Fish Mooney's place.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com